[Music]
join us as Auto X turns 17 we are almost
adults emphasis on the word
[Music]
almost but what we've learned through
our adolesence is how to test best cars
and bikes to near destruction to tell
you which ones are the absolute best of
the Year this is the Auto X best of 2023
Mega test emphasis on the word
[Music]
Mega so yes that was some glimpses of
our annual Mega test at the IAT facility
but we thought we sit down catch our
breath take a breather recollect our
thoughts after those adrenaline fill
days and talk to the jury members talk
to each other and find out just how it
went so of course I'm starting off with
a road test editor shiang B welcome
thank you the first question I have for
you how were your last two days at IAD I
think it was very hectic for me first
first of all because there were so many
cars and bikes I mean we had over 40
contenders yes and of course it's not
just shooting testing but we also want
to enjoy those machines right so there
was a lot going in those 48 Hours think
I think because we just were running
around so it was fun but it was also a
lot of work lot of hard work right so a
lot of hard work but I would like to you
know pick out your brains one after the
other about several things but I want to
start start off
with first understanding how you are as
a rider because our viewers who are
watching this sit down session they
would want to relate to your opinions by
comparing their riding Style with you so
first it's important to know the jewry
as well so what kind of a rider are you
I know it's a loaded question but what
would I think I think for me because we
had such a varied sort of you know
lineup this year we had a lot of naked
motorcycles and in my previous if you
have seen our podcast I said the nakeds
are the best so we had a lot of nakeds
this time but we also at the s000 R so
the moment I was riding the s000 R I
thought oh I'm like a super bike Guy
this is the motorcycle that I want I can
live with the compromises but at the
same time when I was riding the nakeds I
was like okay the monster SP or even the
KTM 390 Duke I thought those were the
best bikes I think long story short if I
have to relate myself I'd say sports
bike guy specially performance guy but a
hint of practicality yeah but yeah
exactly so naked I mean technically you
can say a naked motorcycle guy so I I'd
want a motorcycle that I can ride
everywhere uh so yes that's that's what
so we'll get to the bikes but what I
first want to ask is how was the IAD
testing facility I think it was fun it
was a little challenging because I've
not ridden a motorcycle around an oal
track especially the banking so it was a
little scary at first because the grip
levels would change and especially if
you're on high capacity motorcycle like
the davl monster or the s000 RR so it is
really difficult but again it was fun
because you could push the motorcycle to
the Limit you're also breaking heart
then we created that section with cones
and everything so quick Direction
changes you can figure out what the
motorcycle was doing so when you make
those quick Direction changes you can
feel what the chassis is up to what the
suspension is up to which bike is set up
differently in the sense let's say when
you ride a KTM and you write a speed you
can make out the difference uh in terms
terms of the damping the compression you
know the remount the adjustable
suspension there was a lot kind of to
absorb so I think yeah the I get in that
sense it was a little more objective I'd
say right so every year we guys put
together a whole bunch of motorcycles
where we try to find the best and it's
the first selection criteria is that
they have to be good enough to be a
contender for the coveted best of 2023
award uh we had a good lineup wide
variety of motorcycles and a scooter
what I want to know is what was your
first thought when you saw the lineup
parked there when you arrived for
testing I think again I think I spoke to
you also of the record that you know we
had great motorcycles this year very
interesting motorcycles especially uh I
think they're more relevant in the
largest scheme of things because most of
the motorcycles were 300 to 500 CC then
again in the high segment we had the
monster SP we had the DI V4 we had the
s000 so all basically this is hot metal
technically right so we had all the
motorcycles that you'd want to exploit
the performance on the track I think for
me uh it was a very how do I say it it
was a very rich sort of mixture that we
got there but there must be one that
stood out and you would be like you know
what I'm going to like that one first
what was that for you I think that for
me would be the s000 RR uh it's a great
motorcycle but I really wanted to have a
go on the DI V4 because that engine I
absolutely love and Di uh it's a
confusing motorcycle it's very I mean
it's the motorcycle that you want to
love but you don't understand it so I
wanted to understand what the DL V4
would do especially with that engine
that engine from the multi or the pagali
V4 so there was a lot of change and and
I wanted to see if it would justify the
high price tag right so we know what has
caught your fancy in the high-end
premium bikes it's the V4 deservedly so
but we have to talk about the 400 cc
segment it's all the craze right now in
India and we were the first ones to
actually put the big four together the
KTM 390 Duke the tri speed 400 the
Apache RTR 310 and the harleydavidson
x440 a very varied lineup good bikes in
their own right but what stood out for
you I think all of the these motorcycles
are totally different apart from the KTM
and the RTR I think because the speed is
totally different the Harley is a
cruiser and all that but I think these
are the four biggest launches of the
year uh but if I have to pick one I
think uh the speed 400 for me would be
the motorcycle that kind of changed the
segment because it is a great motorcycle
it does everything it doesn't get
anything extra it just hits the right
spot and then on top of that the pricing
is just out of this world I mean
that's crazy pricing you know if I have
to rank these motorcycles I'd say the
triph is number one for me the KTM is
number two RT number three and Harley is
fourth interesting we've got rankings
now right quick question if you were to
steal one of the bikes from our lineup
what would you take
home wow I was actually thinking what
motorcycle would I buy if I win a
lottery just buy or steal whatever but
like one thing that you just grab the
keys and go away wow that's an
interesting question I mean I would be
very confused of course it's going to be
but you have to pick one and you have to
pick one quick I think the s000
r all right so now Shian I'm going to
put you in the deep end okay of Rapid
Fire questions so I'm going to name some
motorcycles you have to tell me the
first thing that comes to your mind and
it has to be quick so I'm going to start
off with the shine 100
boring
Apache RTR
310 nearly there the 390
Duke
complete the Triumph Speed 400 Game
Changer interesting the hero
Zoom if it takes so long it's not rapid
fire I know but hero Zoom I'd
say stylish
H well played the Charisma XMR 80%
Legend
20% it's not there super medor
650 great
effort but not for
India the ultraviolet
f77 electrifying but a little
shocking right have we come to the big
ones I I I guess I have an idea but Di
will
V4
Sinister the desert
X I'm running out of words now
objectives actually so I think the
desert X would be it's all about X
Factor so H all right the monster
SP better than I expected and finally
the s1000
r the rocket ship all right now at this
point I want to move on to the next jury
member of the motorcycling Squad so
Shang would you do the honors of
swapping seats exactly and put me on the
hot seat I'd ask you different questions
though sure bring
it okay now I'm the host yeah you you
want my cards it's got bike names I I
now I remember everything and your
answers have to be different to what I
said I have been asked Okay so so okay
this first
question that hi I'm manav sin hi nice
meeting you pleas seen you somewhere I
think so 5 minutes not five minutes like
10 seconds all right okay so so we'll
get going again so the first question
I'm going to throw at you is the same
what did you think about the lineup we
had great motorcycles so what did you
think when you saw all those 13
motorcycles 12 motorcycles and one
scooter there very
honestly well for those of you who don't
know of mayo uh it's my first year here
at the autox now before I joined here
shivang and I have been good friends and
I sort of we um have
different racer tastes in Moto GP if I
put it like that and because of which we
have a lot of social media um
discussions interactions uh so I've
always seen those pictures where you
know you have a big lineup of cars and
bikes lined up for the Mega test and for
me it the it sure like the vehicles were
obviously exciting but for me it was
more about you know being there so now
I'm getting the stuff done rather than
just seeing the final version of it so
that was a different experience for me
and the lineup for me it was it was
impressive it it wasn't focusing in one
area that this is what we have or this
is what we don't have I think it was
spread across so there were a lot of
things to go around so I think that way
it was I was beyond impressed that's
that's a good answer thank you very much
but uh coming back to the lineup now you
tell me what's the motorcycle that
surprised you the most right and what's
the motorcycle that disappointed you the
most and what's the motorcycle that
impressed you the most let's put it
three three three big loaded questions I
think before that though I'd like to
share what kind of a writer I am on once
again exactly I'm sorry I
forgot it's okay we'll get there
so for
me it's about going all out and having
the experience the motorcycle is
intended to give right so what happens
with me is if I'm riding a Performance
Bike I want to ride it like a hooligan I
want to shift at the red line I want to
go down a couple of gears and rev match
and do that or if I'm cruising then I
want to like really take it easy and not
in a crazy way but the generic riding
around I think I doesn't excite me that
much so having said that the maximum I
could do with any of the bikes would be
the one that would stood out for me and
that was the
s1000a I know it's it's predictable but
there are two long Straits of course two
long Straits two Banks I mean and just
the the way it stands right the full fed
High tail big tire at the back it speaks
to me like that's I mean of course I'm I
don't have the physique anymore I used
to have as you know few years ago when
we were at the track but it's still that
that genre still speaks to me so the
s1000 r stood out and what's the
motorcycle that surprised you and
disappointed you can be the same
also it could be surprisingly
disappointing uh well okay uh no
thankfully it's not the same uh
so the most uh surprising for me was The
Monster uh disappointing
I disappo I see how it is to be on the
other end of the question I mean
something that's let's not call it
disappointing like underwhelming
underwhelming probably like expected
more from that
motorcycle I really have to think I
think it
was very sadly the Harley Davids and XO
40 um an affordable Harley is of course
a dream for many um The Bike by itself
is good like there's nothing wrong with
it right but we had the big four yeah
and the Harley Davidson x440 by itself
super exciting super impressive but now
the launch is done and there are three
more launches so now when you put those
four together because I really think
they go within the same of yeah pricing
probably yeah yeah and appeal per se
because Triumph badge Harley badge or
performance or this that I think I I I
think the Harley Davidson should have
done better not saying it's bad did well
but I think that lasting memory as you
said like it's rank four for you it was
rank four for me as well so yes I I
think the harer Davidson should have
been more true so for your rapid rapid
fire I think I've got may we have a
rapid fire so no for the rapid fire I've
kind of peaked it because I'm sure when
I was answering you kind of thinking in
your head that I'm going to you're kind
of collecting all the words in your head
is what I'm going to use so I'm going to
do a little twist plot twist here okay
so I'm going to ask you questions about
all the motorcycles but uh what I'm
going to do is uh instead of saying what
do you think about the motorcycle you
have to tell me the best and the worst
thing about that motorcycle oh wow
something that you love and something
that he hatte it and I'm going to change
the sequence it's not going to
controversial let's go exactly that will
be the good thing so let me start with
the Charisma zmr XMR I'm
sorry that's the bad thing it's not the
zmr oh the good thing it's a
Charisma o what an answer very very
diplomatic but anyway we'll take that no
okay okay on a serious
note what it should have been was the
Charisma 440 that sounds right Charisma
was always the bigger bag of the lot
right like the Suzuki boys and the Pulsa
boys they do their thing and then you
show up in a Charisma uh it's too small
for today like we have the big four
exactly Charisma should have been there
so that's is and what's the good part
what's something that's perfect with
that it's still alive the brand lives so
maybe of bigger Charisma like you know
the X pulse is getting bigger maybe the
kisma hopefully gets biger okay so next
one uh super meteor 650 what I don't
like suspension being mounted right
under my sweet
bum it translates all the bumps right to
your spine nature of the motorcycle as
you said not for our country I wish that
wasn't the case what I like is it gives
you the big bike feel s000
R
Performance the exhaust not I'll change
that so that inline four screamer you
don't get screamer super bikes now right
s 1,000 R but I don't like I'm not a big
fan of wings unless they're like trays
like ailia but we're diverging okay yeah
okay the next one is Harley
x440 what I
like budget badge
value okay and bargain deal bargain deal
and what I don't enjoy that
much should have been a proper Cruiser
proper not none of that sport star stuff
proper laidback playing to harle
strength Cruiser cool Apache RTR
310 I like that they're bringing
features to Performance as a whole but I
I don't like the looks to be very Frank
I I'm not a big fan moving on
Monster what I like exhaust not what I
love exhaust not
what I don't
love what do I don't love the headlight
maybe anyway the next bike or scooter is
hero Zone that's the only
scooter what I love practical was the
most practical two wheeler that we had
and uh what I don't seems like the end
talk okay it's it's a wnab product
that's yeah I mean they are clearly
trying to do what the end talk did and
not
quite the size of the company that's
doing it they can create an own identity
they don't have to go after what the end
of does
okay Dia V4 I'm not a big fan of the
tail section of the bike okay uh what I
like what I love the exhausts the four
exhausts okay I'm all about that sound
okay now this is interesting one the
ultraviolet
f77 I like they're not a I love that
they're not ashamed of what they're
trying you can't possibly say you love
the exhaust note yeah not this time but
what I don't like is I want more I think
they can do much more elaborate like
this is something Performance top speed
I EV limitation it wears off very
quickly I I want to see more yeah I me
it's a quick City bike yeah exactly and
cool looking as well Gooding okay speed
what I love is premium on a budget what
I
don't plain Jan
design desert
x what I
love Stand Out Factor what I don't
ducatti
pricing I watering 390 Duke perfect I
love it I love how mad it is it just
goes right up my alley like if I were to
ride it I ride it for 15 minutes have a
good time park it but what I don't love
is very honestly it's a KTM and if it
wasn't a KTM I would have bought it I
would have I don't want to be seen on a
KTM it has an image problem I'll just be
blunt but that's what I don't love and
the last
is the Honda shine Honda wow I kept the
I kep the best for the
last well what do I love
utilitarian okay to put it nicely what
do I don't that it
exists it's it's yeah I mean I I started
my motorcycle Journey with
100cc
bike over a decade ago yeah I didn't
feel the segment has gone anywhere it's
like going back like I said back in time
yeah it was like yeah I can easily swap
the two by but yeah and for the time
being that's what it is and I take my
seat and my lovely cards yes thank you
very much the cards and then I think we
have other people coming in yes so it's
now time to move on for me to leave and
you to come back to your come back thank
you very much for taking my questions
see you
guys so next up what I have for you is
Mr duu Pall our resident craziest Rider
that we have and that's in a good way
because I've rarely seen anyone push
motorcycles like he does so I think
before we start this interview D I want
to ask you and I want the viewers to
know from you what kind of a rider are
you oh that's tough one to begin with
manav honestly speaking and thank you
for calling the craziest Rider but I
think that tag Now lies with Karan Maur
it's it's up for dispay we'll figure
that out uh as far as what kind of
writing is is up my alley I think I'm
someone who looks fast to other people
but in my head every action every
movement every every decision I take on
the road is very calculated but um I
think I'm someone who tries to go as
fast as possible within a certain set of
constraints I have placed for myself and
I think that reflects in the way I love
my motorcycles also um I think in that
setup the most amount of fun you can
have is probably on a naked and that's
why I prefer those kind of motorcycles
where my opinions are coming from I
think I as a journalist at least I try
to be as um relatable to the other guys
possible I think that's a big part of
our jobs where you don't only put in
your opinion um in the Limelight but you
also think that wait okay I have this
particular feeling about a motorcycle
but is it necessary that every single
person who rides this motorcycle will
have uh an opinion like that so I try
and balance those out when it comes to
it but I think uh where I come from is I
think I love speed um the first thing I
would want to do on any motorcycle that
I sit down is find out how fast it can
go so that's where I'm coming from so so
what was the first bike that caught your
eye when you saw the lineup when I saw
the bikes would you like to guess which
one it was the s1000 yes yes there was
no other motorcycle I wanted to sit on
as as badly as I wanted to sit on that
motorcycle and that there's a reason
behind that the
might be controversial but the s000 RR
not this gen this is the facelift the
the this gen and the one before this
with the asymmetrical headlight has been
my dream motorcycle I know people like
their Kawasaki people like their
Hayabusas not for me what was your first
thought when you saw the entire lineup
of the contenders for the best of 2023
uh I was very surprised we didn't have
any electric scooters this time um and
uh but but but but another thing I was
looking forward to was the the
ultraviolet I mean the f77 the thing is
I went for the ride I've ridden that
motorcycle previously um and I was very
excited because I've put the f77 through
its spaces on a go-kart track I've put
it through Paces on nandi hills in
Bangalore uh but I wanted to see how it
would fair when it had other ice
motorcycles next to it what people would
be thinking about it then what I would
think about it so but apart from
electrics we also had some stupendously
fast and good looking motorcycle so
let's take both of them at a time what
was the best looking motorcycle desert
X
okay it's it's a it's a two-c thing I
don't think it's the prettiest looking I
don't think it's the prettiest but it's
the best looking the fact that I can on
the street ride a motorcycle that looks
so close to that it came out of dhar I
think that just sells it that that idea
just sells it for me it just makes it
look prettier now coming to the big four
uh because that's perhaps the most
happening segment right now definitely
the Apache RTR 310 the tri speed 400 the
KTM 390 Duke and the har Davidson x440
all of them together at a controlled
environment to test and push them to the
Limit what stood out for you okay so
what stood out for me this is not my
best motorcycle per se but I think a lot
of people didn't like it but I think the
x440 the Harley dson it stood out for me
it's not a complete motorcycle yet I
would say this still uh in the sense
that just about when you're starting to
have fun on it it reaches its limit in
sense of the rev limiter in sense of I
think the surprising part about that
motorcycle which actually made it stand
out for me was the cornering ability I
think if you just go into a corner with
the right speed with the right angle
with the right attack mindset in mind it
is surprisingly stable I would not say
Nimble but it's surprisingly stable very
confidence inspiring around the banking
it was one of the more confidence
inspiring motorcycles for me me anything
that stood out for you something that
you didn't expect would do so well shine
man I mean it's a Honda yeah it's
just despite you know when you have
motorcycles like these on test it can be
very easy to forget a small displacement
motorcycle but the shine was always
somewhere around in the corner you find
yourself looking at it for like 2
minutes you like yeah I you still felt
like I want to see what it feels like on
the track it had something about it that
you did not want to miss like you know
you you didn't feel like okay it doesn't
belong in this company OB it doesn't
belong in that company but it didn't
feel out of place right with that I
think it's the right time to throw you
in the pit of rapid
fire so I'm going to keep it very simple
okay I'm going to name the motorcycles
we had on test and you have to mention
the first thing that comes to your mind
it can be a word it can be a sentence
can be an expression whatever all right
so I'll
start with the heroes
zoom eh the shine
100 the Apache RTR
3 slow down the Triumph Speed 400
wow the harleydavidson
x440 the KTM 390
Duke I I I don't think we can show that
expression on camera but yeah so that's
how you feel about the 390 the Charisma
XMR I can see why they did it m I'm not
sold all right we come to the big ones
the ultraviolet
f77
Pioneer interesting the DL
V4 I'd rather look at it than ride it
the desert X
I'd rather ride it than look at it but I
want to look at it also okay the monster
SP uh I like nakeds never really like
the
monster it's the one bike I'm a little
indifferent on I would just say it's
okay the super meteor 650 I just wish
our roads were better I think that's
what the super metor tells me please
make your roads better improve your
roads okay ds1000
RR I mean okay how do I this is why I
would have a if there was any reason I
would have a criminal record it would be
d000
d000 like okay thank you D it's been a
pleasure thank you Mana for taking us
back to the track it was lovely doing
this and I think we should tell Dru Dru
Dru we should do more of these I think
we should do two of these in a year me
maybe once a 3 month there a lot of
launches yeah I mean I mean I think we
can split the vehicles into two
house what do you mean Oh you mean the
set of vehicles yes all
right I thought I thought that's some
test all right thank you very much thank
you all right so we have finally got the
man who's difficult to catch hold of um
we are shooting it slightly at a
different time that's because Where Have
You Been these days Mr Karen well I was
in Pune and then I had to head out of
town for a bit with some friends and I'm
going to Bombay again so it gets a
little difficult to squeeze in all this
PTC and everything yeah we got to sit in
the studio I like bikes and get it over
you just want to do jewelry Duty I just
want to get right bikes but jewy Duty
dictates Duty that you to sit with me
and tell me how your experience was so
before we start this is a question I've
been asking all jury members what kind
of a rider are you I have very limited
fear when it comes to riding motorcycles
uh fortunately unfortunately so that the
other aspects of riding a motorcycle
which involve mileage uh
practicality they don't really matter to
me much I just want to go fast between
two red lights and that's what excites
me the most that's what bikes are meant
for right now that's established we were
at the IAT facility there were no red
lights how did that go uh there were
turns between going fast and there was
stoppage involved I don't like that but
it was pretty fun uh time I think the
the track and the slum course and
everything which went into uh trying to
make the IAT test track facility as fun
as possible I think it went well like we
got to experience the small and the
slower bikes in a more detailed Manner
and the bikes in a more uh by the pants
of your seat by the seat of your pants
manner similar same thing similar right
but what was not similar was the lineup
that we had so our best of 2023 lineup
was very exhaustive I've spoken to other
jury members they've given their takes
on what our lineup of bikes and a
scooter represents the best of 2023
contenders right so it gives an image of
how the years gone by for the segment so
when you look at the lineup what do you
think varied like I think we had a very
different uh set of bikes starting with
the hero Zoom I think that was like a
sporty practical scooter then we went on
to the most practical motorcycle which
came out there which is the Honda shine
100 and going all the way up to the BMW
s1000 R it just gives you a sense of
perspective of what motorcycling is all
about like everything is designed for a
purpose everything serves a purpose and
once
you uh appreciate it for what it is I
think it it comes out in a different
light and that's what I really
appreciate about the test so as you said
variety but I'm sure the moment you
turned up saw the lineup in all its
Glory what was the first two wheeler
that caught your fancy
and why yeah I think the
F I've written this in my story you guys
read the magazine I wasn't excited about
the BMW I was excited about the BMW
s1000
uh like the most exciting product which
we had there was probably the dugat
desert X I've had I've heard so many
raving reviews about it about its
capability and to be honest that's what
I first uh swung a leg over
the bike was tall and uh First
Impressions were that this would
probably be really difficult to ride has
a lot of power so managing that power
while trying to uh manage the dimension
of the motorcycle would probably be
difficult but wasn't it was just like it
conformed around you uh the the retro
design was just spot on I think that
desert X impressed me the most so it
wasn't in its natural habitat right it
wasn't not all but you're also one of
the first journalist in the country to
write the desert X yeah even though it
was not in its environment you seem
impressed oh what a machine like so I
would admit I didn't get to test it to
its true capability which is off-road
but at the track the way you could just
pick it up swing it around just from
side to side corner to corner I felt
like I was on a 250cc motorcycle it just
it's it feels light it feels agile and
that's a big St yeah it is a big
statement and it truly felt so there was
like for me something uh as agile as uh
the desert X in I don't think there was
anything as as uh throwable as the
desert X so the big four were there at
our track test how was that experience
it was fun testing them back to back
that's what I'd say like you test them
individually they will impress
individually but once you test them back
to back that's where the pros and the
cons uh come out and to be honest they
were really close uh the top most
contenders obviously were the Duke 390
and the speed 400 these two are uh the
most sporty motorcycles these two are
the probably the
most uh fun motorcycles to ride for
anyone who is getting into that segment
speed 400 goes a little further than the
Duke 390 because it brings in comfort
and brings a bit of uh a little tad bit
uh T more quality to the mix so overall
I think as overall package the speed 400
came out on top the Duke 390 came out on
top as the best ride then then came the
you were popping some wheelies weren't
you I was popping some I couldn't help
myself like all all I was doing I was
riding and the clutch slipped and the
the throttle the throttle cable came
open and the front wheel was in the air
as it happens as it happens sometimes
all right you shared your thoughts yeah
but
uh here's something I've been doing with
everyone okay I'm going to read out the
names of every U motorcycle that is
competing okay as a contender for the
best of 2023
title you have to quickly tell me what
they are starting with the Honda
shine comfortable the hero Zoom
practical the Apache RTR 310 feature
loaded holiday with an
x440
fast see you didn't give me time to
think
right trium speed
400 best of all best of both ons wow
just gave it away didn't you yeah what
you are
after KTM Duke 390 bistic kisma XMR
21 return of Legend all right we get to
the big ones yeah the Dr will
V4 Street
presence the monster
SP
Nimble the desert
X fun here's a quick one ultraviolet
f77 interesting a super meteor
650 just quality of Parts all right the
s1000
RR I think that that should be your
answer dream dream dream all right thank
you very much Karen thank you it's been
a
pleasure
[Music]
he